@jgoley (803) 767-3375 JGoley@gmail.com jonathangoley.com | github.com/jgoley

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

A team player who possesses both the analytical mind of a programmer and the creativity of an artist. Jonathan has 10 years of work experience in the non-profit sector where he refined skills in web development, multimedia production and project management. He seeks work opportunities that inspire creative expression and professional growth.

### **KEY SKILLS**

Web development: JavaScript (Meteor, Backbone, JQuery, Coffeescript), HTML5 (Jade), CSS3 (Stylus, SASS, Bourbon,

Neat), PHP, MySQL, mobile responsive development, GIT

**Graphics/Photography:** Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Google SketchUp

Video/Audio: HDSLR video capture, Premiere, Audition

# **EDUCATION**

**The Iron Yard** | Aug - Nov 2014 Front-End Engineering

University of South Carolina | May 2005 BFA | Art Studio with a photographic concentration GPA: 3.7 (Cum Laude)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### EcoHealth Alliance | New York, NY | (January 2015 - present)

#### Front End Developer and Photographer/Videographer

- - Front end development: Meteor.js, JavaScript (CoffeeScript), HTML (Jade), CSS (Stylus)
- - UI/UX design and development
- Logo and visual brand identity design (Illustrator)
- - Print design (scientific publications and posters) (InDesign)
- Photography document programs and events (Photoshop)
- Videography document programs and events (HDSLR capture)
- - Edit video productions that highlight the organization's programs and mission (Premiere, Audition)

### Columbia Museum of Art | Columbia, SC | (February 2006 - present)

#### Web and Digital Media Consultant | (August 2014 – present)

- Execute technical changes to website
- Maintain exhibition tour application and add tour content

#### Senior Digital Media Manager | (January 2014 - August 2014)

- Designed, developed and maintained the CMA website and exhibition webpages
- Created content for and developed exhibition multimedia tours
- Created multimedia content for the Museum's quarterly electronic publication
- Managed and trained multimedia production assistant
- Shot and edited video productions to market exhibitions and educate museum patrons
- Photographed events and artwork for publication
- Managed the production and installation of exhibition signage

Digital Media Manager | (July 2012 - December 2013)

- Created the technical infrastructure for an interpretive exhibition tour program to enhance visitor experience (tours.columbiamuseum.org)
- Created electronic versions of the Museum's quarterly publication: Collections
- Initiated an ongoing partnership with IT-oLogy to develop relationships with tech companies
- Coordinated and lead an interdepartmental web-team

#### Assistant Preparator & Digital Image Technician | (October 2009 - July 2012)

- Initiated and executed a complete re-design of the Museum's website
- Optimized the Museum's digital imaging workflow

#### Assistant Preparator | (February 2006 - July 2012)

- Team-player in the installation of major exhibitions composed of 2D and 3D objects
- Used extreme care and attention to detail when preparing artwork for installation

#### **HONORS AND AWARDS**

CMA Director's Award (Staff Person of the Year), 2010 Contemporaries' Artist of the Year - CMA, 2009 Eagle Scout Award, Boy Scouts of America, 1999

#### **ACTIVITIES AND SERVICE**

New York Cares Volunteer | March 2015 - present NYC Beekeepers Association Member | 2015-present Columbia Museum of Art Volunteer | 2015 - present Beekeeping Mentor (MSBA) | 2013 - 2015 Habitat for Humanity Volunteer | 2012 - 2015 Assistant Scout Master | 2006 - 2011